const e="We could not find what you asked for, but got you this",i="commerce",t=200,o=120,a=[{id:621,question:"The organized efforts of consumers to protect themselves against the unfair practices of businessmen is called",option:{a:"strike",b:"consumerism",c:"amalgamation",d:"propaganda"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1990"},{id:771,question:"One major characteristic of credit unions and thrift societies is that",option:{a:"the legal processes involved in their formation are rigid",b:"membership compulsory to people in the same line of  business",c:"the contribution of every member depends the member’s ability",d:"a minimum of ten people in the same line of business can form the union"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:626,question:"The law which stipulates that labels should give an accurate account of a product is the",option:{a:"price control act",b:"consumer credit act",c:"trade description act",d:"hire purchase act"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1990"},{id:363,question:"An ancillary to trade that easily links suppliers with consumers is ",option:{a:"tourism  ",b:"banking ",c:"communication ",d:"transportation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:395,question:"The allocation of tasks to different skills in a production process is referred to as ",option:{a:"production technique ",b:"production function ",c:"division of labour",d:"delegation of responsibility "},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:704,question:"The share capital value that forms part of the balance sheet total is the",option:{a:"paid-up share capital",b:"called-up share capital",c:"authorized share capital",d:"issued share capital."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000"},{id:348,question:"The creation of goods and services to satisfy human wants is referred to as ",option:{a:"manufacturing ",b:"commercialization ",c:"Production ",d:"entrepreneurship "},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:710,question:"Tourists with no fixed address in a town may receive their letters from the post office through a",option:{a:"recorded delivery",b:"poste restante",c:"parcel post",d:"postmaster."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000"},{id:194,question:"A new company requiring a large amount of equity finance may source funds from the",option:{a:"capital market   ",b:"central bank",c:"money market    ",d:"commercial banks."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:407,question:"Printed messages sent by cable are recorded as ",option:{a:"telegram ",b:"SMS",c:"telex",d:"MMS"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:763,question:"A factor necessary for siting a warehouse is nearness to",option:{a:"raw materials",b:"labour",c:"capital",d:"consumers."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:234,question:"A historical building is a feature of ",option:{a:"cultural tourism ",b:"industrial tourism ",c:"agricultural  tourism",d:"D. ecological   tourism"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:785,question:"A functional organizational structure is where",option:{a:"staff performing the same functions are grouped together",b:"departments performing similar functions are grouped together",c:"activities of similar nature are-grouped together",d:"staff performing similar functions are grouped together."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:737,question:"The three components of staffing are",option:{a:"recruitment, selection and placement",b:"recruitment, interview and appointment",c:"recruitment, test and placement",d:"recruitment, procurement and appointment"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000"},{id:218,question:"A warehouse which is used to store goods whose customs duty is not yet paid is a ",option:{a:"wholesale warehouse",b:"bonded warehouse",c:"public warehouse",d:"branded warehouse"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:800,question:"Awarding scholarships and sponsoring sports by a business organization are examples of",option:{a:"advertising strategy",b:"economic responsibility",c:"marketing strategy",d:"social responsibility"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:595,question:"Which of the following is NOT an attribute of an effective business manager?",option:{a:"Altruism",b:"Empathy",c:"Objectivity",d:"Subjectivity"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:510,question:"Which of the following is not a means of payment in foreign trade?",option:{a:"Telegraphic money order",b:"Specially crossed cheque",c:"Letters of credit",d:"Debit transfer"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2000"},{id:503,question:"When a country’s total visible and invisible exports are more than its visible and invisible imports, it has",option:{a:"favourable balance of payments",b:"favourable balance of trade",c:"unfavourable balance of trade",d:"unfavourable balance of payments"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2000"},{id:241,question:"The body charged with divesting government interests in public enterprises is ",option:{a:"SON",b:"NPC",c:"BPE ",d:"NDE"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:222,question:"Which ‘FOB’ is written on a document, it implies that the buyer bears the ",option:{a:"cost of goods and advert ",b:"loading cost and insurance ",c:"insurance and transport costs",d:"transport and communication costs"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:227,question:"The four Ps of marketing are",option:{a:"product, place, process and promotion ",b:"price, product, property and place",c:"price, product, place and promotion ",d:"price, production, place and property "},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:213,question:"An account maintained with a commercial bank for the purpose of foreign exchange transaction is the ",option:{a:"foreign account ",b:"International account ",c:"domiciliary account ",d:"foreign reserves account "},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:381,question:"To make a simple contract valid, the intention must be ",option:{a:"legal and written ",b:"legal and binding ",c:"legal and attractive ",d:"legal and harmonious "},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:471,question:"In a staff-authority relationship, the opinion of a specialist is one department to another is ",option:{a:"a directive ",b:"an advice ",c:"a command",d:"a delegation "},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:279,question:"The manufactures’ Association of Nigeria is an example of a ",option:{a:"labour union ",b:"pressure group ",c:"conglomerate ",d:"cartel"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:853,question:"An example of service rendered by NIPOST is",option:{a:"electronic mail",b:"courier",c:"telephone",d:"mail delivery"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:769,question:"The temporary working area of the central processing unit is called the",option:{a:"C-D ROM",b:"C-D RAM",c:"ROM",d:"RAM."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:357,question:"The document which can be exchanged for a bill of lading is ",option:{a:"freight note ",b:"mate receipt ",c:"export invoice ",d:"ship report"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:714,question:"A bank form used to transfer money from personal to creditor’s account is called",option:{a:"debit transfer form",b:"credit transfer form",c:"customer transfer form",d:"bank transfer form."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000"},{id:210,question:"Maimani Plc, whose nominal capital is made up of 500 000 ordinary shares of 50k each, decided to offer 80% of it to the public and realized only 50% of the amount due. What is the company’s authorized share capital?",option:{a:"N2500 000",b:"N4000 0000",c:"N5000 000",d:"N7500 000"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:392,question:"One of the major benefits of commerce to government is to ",option:{a:"improve the standard of living ",b:"generate revenue for growth and development ",c:"encourage cooperation among public organizations ",d:"encourage the development of socio-cultural values"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:596,question:"The ability of money to be divided into smaller units for easy exchange of goods and services explains",option:{a:"divisibility",b:"durability",c:"recognisability",d:"stability"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:283,question:"The function which ensures that set objectives are attained by an organization is ",option:{a:"planning ",b:"directing ",c:"staffing ",d:"controlling "},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:613,question:"Which of the following is a form of sales promotion?",option:{a:"Promotion through radio",b:"Advertising by television",c:"Distributing printed sales literature",d:"Offering free samples to customers"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1990"},{id:356,question:"A document that indicates obligation that is transferable by delivery and endorsement is a ",option:{a:"bill of lading ",b:"bill of exchange ",c:"documentary evidence ",d:"negotiable instrument "},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:333,question:"The label on a product such as ‘pampers’ is a type of ",option:{a:"trademark  ",b:"branding ",c:"packaging ",d:"patent right"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:423,question:"The main objective of a trade association is to ",option:{a:"protect is members against litigation ",b:"boost the trade of its members ",c:"secure credit for its members ",d:"protect its members against victimization "},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:492,question:"A private company is one which",option:{a:"must publish its audited account",b:"floats its shares on the stock exchange market",c:"restricts the rights to transfer its shares",d:"is owned by a maximum of twenty members merger"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2000"},{id:274,question:"The type of partnership in which all partners are jointly liable in bearing risk is ",option:{a:"limited partnership ",b:"partnership-at will",c:"ordinary partnership ",d:"industrial partnership "},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:675,question:"One of the functions of the retailer is",option:{a:"granting credit facilities to close relatives",b:"provision of after-sales services",c:"branding and packaging of goods.",d:"warehousing of goods."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:754,question:"One of the reasons why wholesaling must continue is that",option:{a:"the tax paid by wholesalers on their profit enhances national revenue",b:"by creating artificial scarcity, the wholesaler is enhancing competition in the economy",c:"the wholesaler provides technical advice to the retailer",d:"the gap between manufacturers and retailers is reduced by wholesalers."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:539,question:"Commercialization is good for the Nigerian economy because it",option:{a:"creates room for competition",b:"increases the cost of living",c:"leads to the reduction of workforce",d:"leads to uneven distribution of wealth"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:833,question:"The letters E and OE stand for",option:{a:"errors of exception",b:"errors  and omissions expected",c:"estimated and order error",d:"end of error."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:261,question:"A collective term for advertising, personal selling and publicity is ",option:{a:"exhibition ",b:"promotion ",c:"trade fair ",d:"mechanizing"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:577,question:"The following are merits of industrial integration, EXCEPT",option:{a:"controlling output and price",b:"eliminating waste",c:"leading to monopoly",d:"preventing over production"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"neco",examyear:"2013"},{id:2,question:"Non-insurable risks include ",option:{a:"gambling ",b:"damage to property",c:"death",d:"marine "},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:53,question:"Which part of the computer system does the keyboard device belong to? ",option:{a:"Output unit ",b:" Logic unit ",c:"Input unit ",d:"Control unit."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:652,question:"Which of the following is used for temporary storage of data on a computer?",option:{a:"RAM.",b:"ROM.",c:"floppy disk.",d:"flash disk."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:19,question:"A common element in all contracts is    ",option:{a:"offer",b:"  consideration   ",c:"acceptance ",d:"agreement"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:718,question:"A form of money that has gone out of use is",option:{a:"paper money",b:"bank money",c:"commodity money",d:"foreign money."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000"},{id:205,question:"A document which gives a legal status to a company is the certificate of ",option:{a:"incorporation ",b:"trading ",c:"commencement of business",d:"business registration"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:778,question:"Which of these companies offers after-sales services?",option:{a:"IV",b:"Ill",c:"II",d:"I"},section:"Companies I, II, III and IV produce and sell electronic videos. Company I sells its videos for N= 14 000 each and offers advice on how to fix and operate them. Company II sells at N14 000 and its representatives go to install at no additional cost. Company III sells at N15 500 and offers credit sales at N15 500 per video while company IV sells at N= 15 000 each.",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:72,question:"A partnership is dissolved when",option:{a:"the business suffers a loss",b:"there is bankruptcy",c:"there is consistent theft",d:"there is a misunderstanding between partners"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:655,question:"Which of the following types of occupation involves services that can be referred to as auxiliaries’ trade?",option:{a:"Constructive occupation",b:"Manufacturing occupation.",c:"Industrial occupation.",d:"Commercial occupation"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:355,question:"The three components of a country’s balance of payment are ",option:{a:"Current account, capital account and monetary movement account ",b:"capital account, trade account and business record ",c:"sales account, profit and loss account and capital account ",d:"monetary movement account, trade account and ales ledger."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:468,question:"Gilt-edged securities are issued mainly by ",option:{a:"individuals ",b:"non-governmental organizations",c:"government ",d:"multi-national companies "},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:358,question:"The price quoted which includes the cost of insurance, freight and all delivery charges to the importer’s warehouse is ",option:{a:"Free Alongside Ship",b:"Franco ",c:"Free on Board ",d:"Free on Rail"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:111,question:"The limit of functions, activities and personnel that a supervisor can effectively manage  in a business organization  is  ",option:{a:"spun of control ",b:" delegation of authority ",c:"chain of command ",d:" authority and responsibility"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:34,question:"As the branches indicate, iv is",option:{a:"commerce",b:"exchange ",c:"finance      ",d:"construction"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:640,question:"The word Ltd written after the name of a company means that",option:{a:"the individual member’s capital is limited",b:"the total sum of the company’s capital is limited",c:"members are liable to the extent of their holding",d:"company’s location is limited"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1990"},{id:122,question:"The factor which critically determines the choice of occupation is ",option:{a:"training  ",b:"skill ",c:"interest",d:"aptitude."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:801,question:"The commercialization of public enterprises aimed at",option:{a:"increasing efficiency and making the enterprises self-sufficient",b:"advertising a promoting the goods and services of the enterprises",c:"increased assistance and patronage of the enterprises by the public",d:"selling the goods and services of the enterprises."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:599,question:"The major divisions of Commerce are",option:{a:"import, export and transport",b:"trade, communication and warehousing",c:"trade and auxiliaries to trade",d:"exchange, consumption and production"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"1990"},{id:73,question:"One of the disadvantages of sole proprietorship is",option:{a:"secrecy of annual reports",b:"pride of ownership ",c:"limited liability",d:"unlimited liability."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:14,question:"One important requirement for the membership of the ECOWAS is ",option:{a:"integrity ",b:"independence ",c:"landmass   ",d:"population"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:530,question:"The deliberate and sustained efforts to maintain a good image of a company is known as",option:{a:"personal relations",b:"public relations",c:"professional relations",d:"industrial relations"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2000"},{id:797,question:"Which of the following countries are members the Lake Chad Basin Commission?",option:{a:"Niger and Cameroun",b:"Benin and Niger",c:"Chad and Benin",d:"Nigeria and Mali."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:44,question:"An order sent by an importer to an overseas supplier stating the details of goods required is known as   ",option:{a:"A export invoice    ",b:"ship's manifest",c:"an indent    ",d:"bill of lading"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:682,question:"Labour as an input in production can be motivated by",option:{a:"training",b:"profit.",c:"remuneration.",d:"promotion"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:756,question:"A pro-forma invoice is sent to inform a buyer about the",option:{a:"quantity of goods",b:"prices of goods",c:"designation of goods",d:"quality of goods."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:855,question:"The type of marine insurance which covers either damage or loss to the vessel and such as caused by it to other vessels is",option:{a:"hull insurance",b:"time insurance",c:"freight insurance",d:"cargo insurance"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:162,question:"The sustainable growth of commerce is largely due to ",option:{a:"marketing   ",b:"advertising",c:"exchange ",d:"branding."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:410,question:"Assurance is different from insurance in that the former is based on ",option:{a:"probability ",b:"possibility ",c:"risk ",d:"uncertainty "},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:813,question:"The Stock Exchange is a market where",option:{a:"long-term securities are sold",b:"all types of securities are sold",c:"short-term securities are sold",d:"medium-term securities are sold."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:481,question:"The sole legal right held by the author to publish his book is a ",option:{a:"trademark ",b:"copyright ",c:"patent right ",d:"book mark"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:133,question:"In Nigeria, the main source of pollution is",option:{a:"domestic waste   ",b:"organic waste",c:"gas flaring   ",d:"industrial waste."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:459,question:"Which of the following will NOT be stated in a Memorandum of Association? ",option:{a:"Name clause ",b:"Rights of shareholders ",c:"object clause ",d:"Registered office"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:741,question:"One of the functions of the Niger Basin Commission is to",option:{a:"ensure equal treatment of African nations",b:"foster closer co-operation among West African nations",c:"map out regulations that will guide all forms of navigation",d:"guarantee freedom of navigation for all West African nations."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000"},{id:746,question:"The partner that only contributes part of the capital used in the formation and running of a business is known as",option:{a:"a passive partner",b:"an active partner",c:"a dormant partner",d:"a nominal partner."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:697,question:"The application of division of labour should generally bring about",option:{a:"increase in the quantity of goods and services",b:"increase in the variety of goods and services",c:"cheapness of goods and services",d:"cost efficiency in the production of goods and services."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000"},{id:480,question:"The right of retain possession of goods until the contract price is paid is referred to as ",option:{a:"a promise ",b:"ultra vires ",c:"a branch ",d:"a lien "},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:509,question:"Which of the following refers to a price reduction based on the size of order?",option:{a:"Cash discount",b:"Trade discount",c:"Seasonal discount",d:"Cash on delivery"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2000"},{id:250,question:"Resources harnessed in certain proportion to create goods and services are ",option:{a:"factors of production ",b:"technology and labour ",c:"land and entrepreneur ",d:"raw materials "},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:864,question:"The business organization established mainly for the purpose of carrying out specific assignments for a specific duration is a",option:{a:"joint venture",b:"cooperative society",c:"partnership",d:"company."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:116,question:"What is the capital employed?",option:{a:"N200 000",b:"N340 000",c:"N170 000",d:"N300 000"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2006"},{id:683,question:"Discharging certain duties by an organization to the public to gain high patronage is a concern of financial responsibility",option:{a:"economic responsibility.",b:"legal responsibility.",c:"financial responsibility.",d:"social responsibility."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:63,question:"The type of communication from a superior to a subordinate in an organization is referred to as",option:{a:"horizontal communication",b:"lateral communication",c:"downward communication",d:"upward communication."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2005"},{id:822,question:"A contract for the sale of goods involves the",option:{a:"producer, seller and the buyer of goods",b:"offering of goods to customers",c:"transfer of the title to goods for money",d:"exchange of goods."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:251,question:"Primary production is associated with ",option:{a:"banking ",b:"manufacturing ",c:"agriculture ",d:"construction "},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:209,question:"The components of capital employed in a business are ",option:{a:"owners’ equity and long-term debts ",b:"total assets and current liabilities ",c:"share capital and long-term debts",d:"share capital and current liabilities."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:435,question:"The process of decoding data in a computer is known as ",option:{a:"dilution ",b:"default drive ",c:"decryption ",d:"data security "},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2012"},{id:364,question:"Mr. Lawal insured his warehouse against burglary but it was later gutted buy fire. This implies that ",option:{a:"the loss should be borne by the insurer ",b:"Mr. Lawal is liable  only for half of the estimated loss ",c:"the insurer should make a consolation payment for the loss",d:"the loss should be borne by Mr. Lawal"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2011"},{id:517,question:"A retirement insurance policy which enables the assured to receive income for a specific period is",option:{a:"annuity",b:"endowment",c:"whole life",d:"fidelity guarantee"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2000"},{id:734,question:"The primary objectives of a trade association is to",option:{a:"undertake research work on behalf of members",b:"establish easy link with government",c:"exchange information and negotiate as a pressure group",d:"operate as a group against other groups."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000"},{id:451,question:"The two main forms of communication are ",option:{a:"oral and written ",b:"verbal and non-verbal ",c:"e-mail and fax",d:"traditional and modern media "},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:160,question:"A major function of an entrepreneur is",option:{a:"decision-making ",b:"encouraging competition",c:"human-resource training",d:"motivating employees."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:9,question:"What is the most important use of promotion in marketing?     ",option:{a:"Persuasion   ",b:"Conviction",c:"Information ",d:"Education"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2004"},{id:711,question:"The insurance principle that requires full disclosure of information on the insured is known as",option:{a:"indemnity",b:"uberrimaefidei",c:"subrogation",d:"caveat emptor."},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2000"},{id:856,question:"The management function that makes the difference in intensity of behaviour is",option:{a:"coordinating",b:"controlling",c:"motivation",d:"planning"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:850,question:"A guarantee given by one person or party to another in which 	the integrity of the person is assured is",option:{a:"fidelity",b:"term assurance",c:"subrogation",d:"indemnity"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:531,question:"A contract of sale where ownership passes to the buyer on the payment of the first instalment is known as",option:{a:"hire purchase",b:"lease",c:"cash on delivery",d:"credit sale"},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2000"},{id:845,question:"Goods that are manufactured or acquired by the seller after the contract of sale are",option:{a:"specialty goods",b:"future goods",c:"specific goods",d:"general goods"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2003"},{id:462,question:"A lawyer that defrauds his client may be derobed by the Nigerian Bar Association in order to ",option:{a:"protect other lawyers ",b:"protect the integrity of the association",c:"compensate the affected client ",d:"prevent the client from sueing the association "},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"},{id:525,question:"The marketing activity that stimulates immediate demand for a product is",option:{a:"sales promotion",b:"publicity",c:"consumer relations",d:"personal selling"},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2000"},{id:287,question:"Market skimming is an example of ",option:{a:"market penetration ",b:"Sales promotion ",c:"pricing policy",d:"advertising "},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2009"},{id:789,question:"One of the main objectives of establishing the Niger River Basin Commission was to",option:{a:"embark on a comprehensive survey of the available water resources",b:"carry out research for the development of fresh water fisheries",c:"develop infrastructure to facilitate economic activities",d:"promote trade among member-states to improve standards of living."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:507,question:"Which of the following is sent in reply to a letter of enquiry?",option:{a:"Quotation",b:"Order",c:"Consumer invoice",d:"Advice note"},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"wassce",examyear:"2000"},{id:674,question:"Which of the following is a traditional medium of communication used to mark festivals?",option:{a:"Palm frond.",b:"Metal gong.",c:"Talking drum.",d:"Gun blast."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:158,question:"The controllable variables that a firm uses to achieve its marketing objectives are called",option:{a:"marketing principles ",b:"marketing mix",c:"marketing concepts",d:"marketing functions."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2007"},{id:659,question:"Given: - [Index of export price] / [Index of import price]  x 100  The formula can be used to determine the",option:{a:"terms of payment",b:"balance of payments",c:"terms of trade",d:"import tariffs."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:810,question:"The temporary insurance certificate issued to the insured before drawing up a policy is a",option:{a:"cover  note",b:"testimonial",c:"time policy",d:"proposal  form."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:779,question:"Who are the parties to the contract of renting the room?",option:{a:"Musa and Jacob",b:"Musa and Audu",c:"Adamu and Musa",d:"Audu and Jocob."},section:"Musa rented a room to Adamu for N= 1, 500 and N= 1,000 part-payment was made. Adamu brought Audu and Jacob his friends to stay in the room. The two friends later paid the balance of N= 500 to Musa.",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:760,question:"If  Mr. Bacus fulfils his promise, he will be entitled to a cash discount of",option:{a:"N= 2,760",b:"N= 3,000",c:"N= 6,500",d:"N= 9,500."},section:"Mr. Awala is a retailer of a single product. He sells at the standard price. He gives a trade discount of 5%,quantity discount of 3% for a volume above 1000 units and a cash discount of 2/10 net 30  the existing selling price of the product is N= 100 per unit. Mr. Bacus purchased 1500 units of the product on credit and promised to pay Mr. Awala in cash in the first 10 days after purchase.",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:214,question:"A trader who gives credit stands to enjoy ",option:{a:"higher profit ",b:"cash discount ",c:"increased sales ",d:"trade discount"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2008"},{id:751,question:"The financial instrument for borrowing in which the collateral is usually more than the amount borrowed is",option:{a:"trust certificate",b:"detachable warrant",c:"mortgage bond",d:"convertible securities."},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2001"},{id:824,question:"The process of mobilizing, engaging  and maintaining workers to work for an organization is referred to as",option:{a:"staffing",b:"selection",c:"recruitment",d:"employment."},section:"",image:"",answer:"d",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2002"},{id:313,question:"One of the merits of television as a medium of advertising is that it ",option:{a:"is prone to censorship ",b:"is relatively cheap ",c:"has more sensory stimulation ",d:"has more network coverage"},section:"",image:"",answer:"c",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2010"},{id:685,question:"Which of the following is NOT backed by gold but by government securities?",option:{a:"Fiduciary note.",b:"Fiat money.",c:"Token money.",d:"Commodity money."},section:"",image:"",answer:"a",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2016"},{id:469,question:"The initial function of a manager is ",option:{a:"setting up an organization ",b:"coordinating ",c:"planning ",d:"provision of welfare package "},section:"",image:"",answer:"b",solution:"",examtype:"utme",examyear:"2013"}],n={message:e,subject:i,status:200,total:120,data:a};export{a as data,n as default,e as message,t as status,i as subject,o as total};
